# **DANIEL SZWARC**

YARDLEY, PA · 732-841-7285 · DNLSZWARC@GMAIL.COM · [GitHub] ·

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I am an adaptable, solutions-driven software engineer with a desire to make full-featured products and continually expand my skill set. My previous experience as a mechanical engineer has provided me with the ability to tackle problems head-on, both as an independent and in a team environment. I hope to find a career where I can work with like-minded individuals to solve complex problems and develop dependable, user-friendly solutions.

#### **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Pvthon

FRAMEWORKS/LIBRARIES: Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Bootstrap

TOOLS: Git/GitHub, Node.js

OTHER SKILLS: Microsoft Office Suite, Outlook, Spanish (proficient), Polish (proficient)

## **PROJECTS**

# BATTLESCRIPT | Deployment Link |

- Recreated a classic board game, Battleship, into an interactive JavaScript browser-game
- Used a combination on CSS, HTML, and JavaScript DOM manipulation to place game pieces, change pages, and interact with the user
- Modeled app around an Model, View, Controller (MVC) structure to update and re-render state

## RACQUET-REVIEWER Deployment Link

- Created a modern-feeling, Bootstrap-designed website for users to add and review their favorite tennis racquets using MongoDB, Express, and Node
- Included all CRUD operations as well as following RESTful architecture
- Used third-party resources such as Google Oauth, Atlas, and Cyclic to deploy the app

#### **DEVENTFUL** | Deployment Link |

- Created a web app to help users plan events, keep track of vendors, and keep track of budgets
- Worked in a team of software engineers to create a RESTful app using Python, Django, and PostgreSQL
- Managed GitHub merge and pull requests for my team, as well as creating and support the database and model structures
- Interacted with Google Maps API to show locations for our events

## POKETRACKER Deployment Link

- Designed a fully-featured CRUD app using a full MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js) stack to view and interact with the third-party PokeAPI
- Allowed users to create teams and add Pokemon, utilizing information pulled from JSON response from third party API
- Leveraged API fetch method and state-based rendering to create a single-page React application

#### **EXPERIENCE**

INNO-SPIN, Lead Process Engineer

July 2020 - Jan 2023

- Led team of engineers to increase production of rail seal components from 55,000 pcs per week to 110,000 pcs per week through process improvements
- Decreased machine scrap rate from 2.5% to 1.5% through laser weld optimization, resulting in \$15,000 raw material savings per month
- maintained the continual improvement system, leading to an increase in machine OEE (Overall Equipment Effectiveness) by 33%
- Developed automated excel sheets and use of SAP to ship 250,000+ pcs per week and for tracking of raw material usage
  Led engineering team through IATF 16949 (Automotive ISO 9001 equivalent) audit

DHPC Technologies, Senior Consultant Control Systems Engineer

Jan 2020 - July 2020

- Led a team of engineers to create a proof-of-concept demonstration for OCR (Optical Character Recognition) applications
- Presented research to customers during weekly update meetings detailing the team's proof of concept
- Followed up with my team to ensure projected deadlines were being met
- Programmed vision software including Cognex ViDi Suite and Insight Explorer
- Developed and modeled mounting designs for GigE cameras taking into consideration pre-existing structures

# **EDUCATION**

Software Engineering Immersive, General Assembly, Remote, Feb 2023 - May 2023 Bachelor's of Engineering in Mechanical Engineering, Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, NJ, 2011-2016